### [Internet](https://www.consolidated.com/residential/internet)

          [
        
        #### Learn What You Can Get with Consolidated Internet](https://www.consolidated.com/residential/internet)

        ### [Phone](https://www.consolidated.com/residential/phone)

        ### [STREAMING TV](https://www.consolidated.com/residential/streaming-tv)
        
        Add streaming TV to your Consolidated Internet Service

          [#### View Our Streaming TV Partners for Endless Entertainment Options](https://www.consolidated.com/residential/streaming-tv)

        ### [Small Business](https://www.consolidated.com/business/small-business)

          [
        
        #### Solutions to Meet the Needs of Some Popular Business Applications](https://www.consolidated.com/business/small-business)

        ### [Medium & Enterprise](https://www.consolidated.com/business/medium-enterprise)

          [#### Advanced Services to Support Medium and Enterprise Business](https://www.consolidated.com/business/medium-enterprise)

        ### [Industry Solutions](https://www.consolidated.com/business/industry-solutions)

          [#### Engineering Customer Fiber Builds and Last Mile Connections](https://www.consolidated.com/business/industry-solutions)

        ### [Resources](https://www.consolidated.com/business/resources)

          [#### Documentation and Tools You Need with the Support You Deserve](https://www.consolidated.com/business/resources)

        ### [Services](https://www.consolidated.com/wholesale/services)
        
          [#### Comprehensive Wholesale Digital Infrastructure Solutions](https://www.consolidated.com/wholesale/services)

        ### [Network Maps](https://www.consolidated.com/wholesale/network-maps)

        ### [Resources](https://www.consolidated.com/wholesale/resources)

          [#### Documentation and Tools You Need with the Support You Deserve](https://www.consolidated.com/wholesale/resources)

        ### [Residential Support](https://www.consolidated.com/support/residential-support)

          [
        
        #### Get the Support You Need for Residential Internet, Email, TV, Phone and More.](https://www.consolidated.com/support/residential-support)

        ### [Business Support](https://www.consolidated.com/support/business-support)

          [#### Helpful Business Manuals, User Guides, Brochures and More.](https://www.consolidated.com/support/business-support)

        ### [Account Support](https://www.consolidated.com/support/account-support)

          [#### View or Pay Your Bill, Check Your Email, Login to Customer Portal and More.](https://www.consolidated.com/support/account-support)

        ### [Terms & Policies](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies)

          [#### Access regulatory information, terms and policies, and more for Consolidated Communications services.](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies)

        ### [Alerts](https://www.consolidated.com/support/alerts)

          [#### Customer assistance, important information and helpful tools to help you stay safe and informed.](https://www.consolidated.com/support/alerts)

        * Add streaming TV to your Consolidated Internet Service

* ×
    
    #### Information Varies By Location
    
    #### Additional Information Required
    
    #### Manage Your Service Address
    
    **Please enter your service ZIP code to proceed.**
    
     Search >
    
    Attempting to find your ZIP code...

    Entering your location will apply a cookie that allows us to render location-based service and support information. If you prefer not to use the cookie, please discontinue use of this tool.
    
    ##### Current Address:
    
    Change
    
    Please provide your complete service address, starting with street number.  
    
    Search >
    
    Loading...
    
    Potential address matches will appear as you type. Click your address from the drop-down as it appears or keep typing to refine your search.

    Entering your location will apply a cookie that allows us to render location-based service and support information. If you prefer not to use the cookie, please discontinue use of this tool.
    
    Close
    
    You are in   Change Location
    
    Select Location

 [Search](javascript:__doPostBack('dnn$Header$SiteSearch$cmdSearch',''))

Terms & Policies

Privacy Policy
==============

**CUSTOMER PRIVACY NOTICE**

If you are a customer, please review the section related to our services. [If you are a website visitor, please review the website-specific terms below](#webterms).

**Note to Maine Residents:** Please review the "[Notice to Maine Residents – Your Rights under Maine's 2019 Internet Privacy Law](#merights)" section below for more information about your rights under the 2019 "Act to Protect the Privacy of Online Customer Information" (or the "Maine Privacy Act").

**Note to California Residents:** Please review the “[Notice to California Residents – Your CCPA Rights](#carights)” section below for more information about your rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act (“CCPA”).

**Note to Texas Residents:** Please review the “[Notice to Texas Residents – Your rights under the Texas Data Privacy and Security Act](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-policy/texas-data-privacy-and-security-act)” section for more information about your rights under the Texas Data Privacy and Security Act (“TDPSA).

**OUR SERVICES**
----------------

**Special Note:** This notice only applies to our services. It applies to you as a subscriber to one or more of these services as provided for by applicable law and except as otherwise noted. It does not cover information that may be collected through our websites, even if you access them through our services and even if they are co-branded with Consolidated Communications brands or the brands or logos of our affiliated companies. You should read the privacy policies for these other products, services, and websites to learn how they handle your personal information.

**During the course of providing your services, Consolidated Communications will collect personally identifiable information about you, your preferences and the services we provide you. However, Consolidated Communications does not sell or share your personally identifiable information (as defined below) to any third party or service provider, for any reason that is not directly related to providing you with products and services, except as outlined in this document. We do sometimes use personally identifiable information to offer you new products and services, but you have the ability to opt out of such marketing at any time.**

“Personally identifiable information” is information that identifies a particular person; it does not include de-identified, anonymous, or aggregate data that does not identify a particular person or persons.

In addition, Section 222 of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, (the “Communications Act” or the “Act”) provides additional privacy protections for certain information related to our services:

* information about the quantity, technical configuration, type, destination, location, and amount of your use of the phone and Internet services; and
* information contained on your bill concerning the type of phone and Internet services and features you receive.

That information is known as “customer proprietary network information” or “CPNI” for short. This notice, which includes our CPNI Policy, describes what CPNI information we obtain, how we protect it, and how it may be used. If you use our services, you have the right, and Consolidated Communications has a duty, under the Communications Act and applicable state law, to protect the confidentiality of CPNI.

**Special Note:** Our CPNI Policy applies to all services we deliver to our customers.

In this notice, the terms “Consolidated Communications,” “we,” “us,” or “our” refer to the operating company, subsidiaries or affiliates of Consolidated Communications.

1. ### Collection

**What kind of information does this notice apply to?**

The Act applies to personally identifiable information that you have furnished to Consolidated Communications, or that Consolidated Communications has collected in connection with the provision of services. The Communications Act applies to CPNI related to our regulated phone and Internet services but we apply it to all products and services regardless of their regulatory status.

**For what purposes may Consolidated Communications collect personally identifiable information and CPNI?**

The Act authorizes Consolidated Communications as a service provider to collect personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber for the following purposes:

* to obtain information necessary to render services to our subscribers; and
* to detect unauthorized reception of services.

The Act prohibits us from collecting personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber for any purposes other than those listed above without the subscriber’s prior written or electronic consent.

The Act authorizes us to use, disclose, or permit access to individually identifiable CPNI in our provision of:

* “telecommunications services” (as defined in the Telecommunications Act of 1996, as amended) from which this information is derived; or
* services necessary to, or used in, the provision of these services, including the publishing of directories.

The Act prohibits us from using CPNI for any purposes other than those listed above except as permitted or required by law. We may use your CPNI to market other Consolidated Communications products and services to you unless you notify us that you wish to opt out of such marketing.

**What kind of personally identifiable information and CPNI does Consolidated Communications collect?**

Consolidated Communications collects information from you at several different points when you request, turn on, and use our services under an account we create for you. Some of this information is personally identifiable information. We collect certain personally identifiable information that our subscribers furnish to us in connection with the provision of services. In order to provide reliable, high quality service to you, we keep regular business records containing information about you that may constitute personally identifiable information. These account records may include some or all of the following information:

* your name;
* business name, if applicable;
* service address;
* billing address;
* email address;
* telephone number;
* driver’s license number;
* social security number;
* bank account number; and
* credit card number.

With respect to phone services, examples of CPNI include information typically available from telephone-related details on your monthly bill:

* location of service;
* technical configuration of service;
* type of service;
* quantity of service;
* amount of use of service; and
* calling patterns.

CPNI does not include your name, address, or telephone number. The Act classifies this information as “subscriber list information” which is not subject to the CPNI protections. However, Consolidated Communications treats all subscriber information as CPNI protected.

We also collect and maintain certain other information about your account. For example, this information may include:

* your account number;
* billing, payment, and deposit history;
* additional service information;
* customer correspondence and communications records;
* maintenance and complaint information;
* the device identifiers and network addresses of equipment used with your account;
* records indicating the number of television sets, set-top boxes, modems, telephones, or other devices connected to our network; and
* additional information about the service options you have chosen.

Certain of our services permit you to establish secondary accounts, and if you do so we collect similar information in order to establish and service the secondary accounts. During the initial provisioning of our services, and during any subsequent changes or updates to our services, Consolidated Communications may collect technical information about your televisions, any set-top boxes, computer hardware and software, modems, telephones, other service-related devices, and customization settings and preferences. Additionally, if you rent your residence or business location, we may have a record of whether landlord permission was required prior to installing our services, as well as your landlord's name and address. Subscribers may also authorize others to have access to their account information and grant such authorized users the ability to review and change account information and services.

**What kind of information does Consolidated Communications collect in connection with providing you video services?**

When you subscribe to our video services, information about your use of the services and their features is automatically generated, and we collect much of this information as part of providing services to you. For example, we receive information about the use of set top boxes, remote controls, electronic program guides, video players, applications, and other devices and software connected to our television systems or services. This information includes which channels, programs, and advertisements are viewed and for how long, for example. It may also include information about navigation through program guides and applications, and use of devices like remote controls and tablets. Except in certain circumstances, we collect this data (which we refer to as “activity data”) without names and addresses or other personally identifiable information and we consider it de-identified data. As part of providing you video services, we may collect activity data that includes personally identifiable information for particular requests or transactions you make such as when you order a pay-per-view program or purchase a product. This information typically consists of account and billing-related information such as programs or other products, services, or features ordered so that you may be properly billed for them. We use information about your use of our services for a number of purposes including to determine which programs are most popular, how many people watch a program to its conclusion, and whether people are watching commercials, as well as to improve our services, process transactions and make programming and advertising more relevant to our subscribers. Please see “How does Consolidated Communications use activity data and other data in connection with video services?” for more information about how we use your collected data.

28. ### Use

How does Consolidated Communications use personally identifiable information and CPNI?

We collect, maintain, and use personally identifiable information and CPNI as permitted by the Act and other applicable laws. We use this information primarily to conduct business activities related to providing you with services. Generally speaking, we use personally identifiable information in connection with:

* billing and invoicing;
* administration;
* surveys;
* collection charges;
* marketing;
* service delivery and customization;
* maintenance and operations;
* technical support;
* hardware and software upgrades; and
* fraud prevention.

More specifically, we also use personally identifiable information to:

* install, configure, operate, provide, support, and maintain our services;
* confirm you are receiving the level(s) of service requested and are properly billed;
* identify you as authorized to make changes to your account or services;
* make you aware of new content, products, or services that may be of interest to you;
* understand the use of, and identify improvements to, our services;
* detect unauthorized use or abuse of our services;
* determine whether there are violations of any applicable policies and terms of service;
* manage the network supporting our services;
* configure and update service-related devices and software; and
* comply with law.

The Communications Act further permits Consolidated Communications to use, disclose, and permit access to CPNI obtained from our customers, either directly or indirectly, to:

* initiate, render, bill, and collect for telecommunications services; and
* protect our rights and property, and protect our users of these services and other carriers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, or subscription to, these services.

Unless you notify us that you wish to opt out of our use of your CPNI, Consolidated Communications may use your CPNI to market additional products and services that we offer in accordance with our policies. Consolidated Communications does not share your CPNI with third party marketers for the purpose of selling any third party’s products or services.

Consolidated Communications transmits, and may collect and store for a period of time, personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information about you when you use our network to:

* send and receive email, video mail, and instant messages;
* transfer and share files;
* make files accessible;
* visit websites;
* place or receive calls;
* leave and receive voice mail messages;
* use the applicable services portal;
* establish custom settings or preferences;
* communicate with us for support; or
* otherwise use the services and their features.

Our transmission, collection, and storage of this information are necessary to render the services. In certain situations, service providers may transmit, collect, and store this information on our behalf to provide features of our services. These third parties are not permitted to use your personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these features.

**How does Consolidated Communications use activity data and other data in connection with video service?**

We associate activity data with particular devices such as set top boxes, portable devices, and other supported devices so that we know where to deliver the services and how to troubleshoot them. In general, Consolidated Communications uses de-identified and aggregate activity information to understand better how our customers use our products and services so that we can improve them, including by delivering more relevant content and advertising. We may try to determine how well our products and services deliver value to our customers, for example, by determining which programs are most popular, how many people watch a program to its conclusion, and whether and how often people are watching commercials. As discussed below, we may also combine activity data with other non-personally identifying demographic and similar information from our business records.

When we collect activity data, we may also use it to determine how many people view commercials (impressions) and to provide de-identified or aggregate reports to third-party advertisers. When we do this reporting on advertising impressions we do not provide any personally identifiable information about our subscribers to third-party advertisers. We, or our service providers, may combine de-identified activity data with other data to determine and report how an advertiser’s messages are viewed, including on other platforms and services.

We may also use activity data to help us learn how popular certain programs are and how our customers as a whole generally prefer to view certain kinds of programming using video service (such as whether they like to watch certain programs live, or they prefer to view them when we offer them on demand, on mobile devices, or online). As described below, this may require us to compare or combine activity data with online activity data. We may also use activity data to determine whether promoting content and services in certain ways helps attract a larger audience and more customers. While we may provide aggregate reports on these observations to programmers or others, we do not provide any personally identifiable information about our subscribers, or the activities of individual subscribers, to those programmers or others.

We may also use, or combine information about, your use of our services with other information we obtain from our business records (such as your Consolidated Communications account number or device identifiers), or from third parties, to deliver better and more relevant products, services and advertising. However, we do not store or share your activity data in association with your name or address, except as necessary to render or bill for our services. We may try to determine, using aggregated data, which groups of our customers use which of our products and services and how they use them. To do this, we or third parties working on our behalf, may combine demographic and other generally available information, or advertiser information, including purchasing data and membership in loyalty programs, with our subscriber lists. From this information, we or our service providers prepare de-identified and aggregated reports about how groups of customers with common characteristics – such as age and gender, or a demonstrated interest in a particular third-party product – use our services and respond to the programming and advertising that we distribute. We may use this information to improve and communicate with you about our own products and services, and also to help us deliver relevant information and advertising on behalf of other companies and advertisers to certain subscriber groups – known as ad groups – who may be most interested in this information and advertising. When we do this, we do not share your personally identifiable information with these advertisers, unless you provide your express consent, and we require third parties to treat all information we provide as confidential and to use it only for Consolidated Communications’ business purposes.

We may also combine personally identifiable information, which we collect as described in this notice as part of our regular business records, with personally identifiable information obtained from third parties for the purpose of creating an enhanced database or business records. We may use this database and these business records for marketing, advertising, and other activities related to our service and other services. We may also work with academic or research interest groups to analyze de-identified, anonymous, and/or aggregate information we provide to them for specific purposes or projects, as well as maintain records of research concerning subscriber satisfaction and viewing habits.

**How does Consolidated Communications use information about use of services on other platforms like websites or mobile applications?**

We may compare or combine information such as activity data we receive when you use video services to view content or advertising with information about your use of content and advertising that we deliver on other platforms, such as on our websites and mobile applications. We may also compare or combine this information or data with that generated by your viewing of advertising placed or sold by Consolidated Communications on other websites and mobile applications. We do this to better understand, among other things, how our customers access and use our products and services in all of the places that we offer them.

53. ### Disclosure

**Under what circumstances may Consolidated Communications disclose personally identifiable information to others?**

Consolidated Communications considers the personally identifiable information contained in our business records to be confidential. The Act authorizes Consolidated Communications as a service provider to disclose personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber if the disclosure is:

* necessary to render, or conduct a legitimate business activity related to, the service or other services provided to the subscriber;
* required by law or legal process (described below under “When is Consolidated Communications required to disclose personally identifiable information and CPNI by law?”); or
* of the names and addresses of subscribers for “mailing list” or other purposes (subject to each subscriber’s right to prohibit or limit this disclosure and the CPNI Policy described below under “[How do I place myself on Consolidated Communications’ ‘do not call’ and ‘do not mail’ lists?](#donotcalllist)”).

The Act prohibits us as an operator from disclosing personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber for any purposes other than those listed above without the subscriber’s prior written or electronic consent.

**To whom may Consolidated Communications disclose personally identifiable information?**

We may disclose personally identifiable information as provided for in the Act when it is necessary to render, or conduct a legitimate business activity related to, services we provide to you. These kinds of disclosures typically involve billing and collections, administration, surveys, marketing, service delivery and customization, maintenance and operations, incident verification and response, service notifications, fraud prevention, and services to improve our programming and advertising offerings. We may also collect, use, and disclose information about you in de-identified, anonymous, or aggregate formats, such as ratings surveys and service usage and other statistical reports, which do not personally identify you, your particular viewing habits, or the nature of your transactions. The frequency of any disclosure of personally identifiable information varies in accordance with our business needs and activities.

We may also use or disclose personally identifiable information about you without your consent to protect our customers, employees, or property, in emergency situations, to enforce our rights under our terms of service and policies, in court or elsewhere, and as otherwise permitted by law.

**When may Consolidated Communications disclose personal information to others in connection with phone service?**

Consolidated Communications may disclose to others personally identifiable information in connection with features and services such as Caller ID, 911/E911, and directory services as follows:

* We may transmit your name and/or telephone number to be displayed on a Caller ID device unless you have elected to block such information. Please note that Caller ID blocking may not prevent the display of your name and/or telephone number when you dial certain business or emergency numbers, 911, 900 numbers, or toll-free 800, 888, 877, 866 or 855 numbers.
* We may provide your name, address, and telephone number to public safety authorities and their vendors for inclusion in E911 databases and records, inclusion in “reverse 911” systems, or to troubleshoot 911/E911 record errors.
* We may publish and distribute, or cause to be published and distributed, telephone directories in print, on the Internet, and on disks. Those telephone directories may include subscriber names, addresses, and telephone numbers, without restriction to their use.
* We may also make subscriber names, addresses, and telephone numbers available, or cause such subscriber information to be made available, through directory assistance operators.
* We may provide subscribers’ names, addresses, and telephone numbers to unaffiliated directory publishers and directory assistance providers for their use in creating directories and offering directory assistance services.
* Once our subscribers’ names, addresses, and telephone numbers appear in telephone directories or directory assistance, they may be sorted, packaged, repackaged and made available again in different formats by anyone.
* If Consolidated Communications enters into a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, a customer's personally identifiable information will, in most instances, be transferred as a part of the transaction, subject to required notices, if any, to affected customers.
* We may, where permitted by law, provide information to credit bureaus, or provide information and/or sell receivables to collection agencies, to obtain payment for Consolidated Communications billed products and services.
* Under certain circumstances, we may share customer information with other carriers or with law enforcement, for example, to prevent and investigate fraud or other unlawful use of communications services.

We take reasonable precautions to ensure that non-published and unlisted numbers are not included in our telephone directories or directory assistance services, but we cannot guarantee that errors will never occur.  In addition, you may elect to exclude your phone number, name and service address from your local telephone directory and directory assistance for a charge.

**When is Consolidated Communications required to disclose personally identifiable information and CPNI by law?**

We make every reasonable effort to protect subscriber privacy as described in this notice. Nevertheless, we may be required by law to disclose personally identifiable information or individually identifiable CPNI about a subscriber. These disclosures may be made with or without the subscriber’s consent, and with or without notice, in compliance with the terms of valid legal process such as a subpoena, court order, or search warrant.

For subscribers to our video service, Consolidated Communications may be required as an operator to disclose personally identifiable information to a third party or governmental entity in response to a court order. If the court order is sought by a non-governmental entity, we are required under the Act to notify the subscriber of the court order. If the court order is sought by a governmental entity, the Act requires that the subscriber be afforded the opportunity to appear and contest in a court proceeding relevant to the court order any claims made in support of the court order. At the proceeding, the Act requires the governmental entity to offer clear and convincing evidence that the subject of the information is reasonably suspected of engaging in criminal activity and that the information sought would be material evidence in the case.

For subscribers to our high-speed Internet and phone services, Consolidated Communications may be required to disclose personally identifiable information and individually identifiable CPNI to a private third party in response to a court order, and, if so, we are required to notify the subscriber of the court order. Consolidated Communications may also be required to disclose personally identifiable information and individually identifiable CPNI about subscribers to high-speed Internet and phone services to a government entity in response to a subpoena, court order, or search warrant, for example. We are usually prohibited from notifying the subscriber of any disclosure of personally identifiable information to a government entity by the terms of the subpoena, court order, or search warrant.

Consolidated Communications is also required by law to provide billing name and address information to a customer's long distance carrier and other telephone companies to allow them to bill for telecommunications services. By law, customers with non-published or unlisted service have the right not to have their billing name, address and phone number disclosed when they make a calling card call or accept a collect or third-party call. However, if you do restrict disclosure, you will be unable to make calling card calls or accept collect and third-party calls.

**How does Consolidated Communications protect personally identifiable information?**

We follow industry-standard practices to take such actions as are necessary to prevent unauthorized access to personally identifiable information by a person other than the subscriber or us. However, we cannot guarantee that these practices will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use, or disclose personally identifiable information.

**How long does Consolidated Communications maintain personally identifiable information?**

Consolidated Communications maintains personally identifiable information about you in our regular business records while you are a subscriber to our services. We also maintain this information for a period of time after you are no longer a subscriber if the information is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or to satisfy legal requirements. These purposes typically include business, legal, or tax purposes. If these purposes no longer apply, we will destroy, de-identify, or anonymize the information according to our internal policies and procedures.

77. ### Customer Access and Preferences

**How can I see my personally identifiable information or CPNI and correct it, if necessary?**

You may examine and correct, if necessary, the personally identifiable information regarding you that is collected and maintained by Consolidated Communications in our regular business records. In most cases, the personally identifiable information contained in these records consists solely of billing and account information. We will correct our records if you make a reasonable showing that any of the personally identifiable information we have collected about you is inaccurate.

If you make an affirmative, written request for a copy of your CPNI, we will disclose the relevant information we have to you at your account address of record, or to any person authorized by you, if we reasonably believe the request is valid. However, subscribers to our phone services should be aware that we generally do not provide them with records of any inbound or outbound calls or other records that we don’t furnish in the ordinary course of business (for example, as part of a bill) or which are available only from our archives, without valid legal process such as a court order. In addition, we cannot correct any errors in customer names, addresses, or telephone numbers appearing in, or omitted from, our or our vendors’ directory lists until the next available publication of those directory lists. Further, we may have no control over information appearing in the directory lists or directory assistance services of directory publishers or directory assistance providers that are not owned by our subsidiaries or us.

Consolidated Communications reserves the right to charge you for the reasonable cost of retrieving and photocopying any documents that you request.

**How do I place myself on Consolidated Communications’ “do not call” and “do not mail” lists?**

You may contact Consolidated Communications at 1.844.YOUR.CCI (1.844.968.7224) to ask us to put your name on our internal company “do not call” and “do not mail” lists so that you do not receive marketing or promotional telephone calls or postal mail from us or made at our request.

If you prefer to contact Consolidated Communications in writing instead of by telephone, you may submit an online request at [www.consolidated.com/contact-us](https://www.consolidated.com/contact-us) or send us a written request to the mailing address listed below under “[How do I contact Consolidated Communications?](#howcontact)"

Be sure to include your name and address, your Consolidated Communications account number, and a daytime telephone number where you can be reached in the event we have any questions about your request. The person who is identified in our billing records as the subscriber should sign the written request. If you have a joint account, a request by one party will apply to the entire account. If you have multiple accounts, your notice must separately identify each account covered by the request.

**What email communications will Consolidated Communications send to me and how do I manage them?**

We may send a welcome email, appointment reminders, order confirmations and other information to subscribers to our services (including new secondary account holders, where applicable). We may also send service-related announcements from time to time and service activation communications to our subscribers. For example, we may send you an email announcement about a pricing change, a change in operating policies, a service appointment, a planned or unplanned service interruption, or new features of one or more of the services you receive from us. You may not opt out of these service-related communications. If you fail to check your primary email address for service-related announcements, you may miss important information about our services, including legal notices, for example. You can update your primary email address by contacting us.

**What can I do if I think my privacy rights have been violated?**

If you believe that you have been aggrieved by any act of ours in violation of the Act or other applicable laws, we encourage you to contact us directly as described below in "[How do I contact Consolidated Communications?](#howcontact)” in order to resolve your question or concern. You may also enforce the limitations imposed on us by the Act as applicable with respect to your personally identifiable information through a civil lawsuit seeking damages, attorneys' fees, and litigation costs. Other rights and remedies may be available to you under federal or other applicable laws as well. This customer privacy notice neither supersedes nor modifies any arbitration agreement to which you may be bound relating to the provision of our video service, our high-speed Internet service or our phone services to you as a subscriber to one or more of these services.

* * *

#### How do I contact Consolidated Communications?

Contact Consolidated Communications regarding the following:

* Place myself on Consolidated Communications’ “do not call” and “do not mail” list
* Contact Consolidated about my CPNI/privacy preferences, including to examine records of my personally identifiable information and to opt out of allowing us to use your CPNI to offer you additional products and services
* Contact Consolidated about this Privacy Policy

To contact us regarding these matters, please call 1.844.YOUR.CCI (1.844.968.7224), submit an online request at [www.consolidated.com/contact-us](https://www.consolidated.com/contact-us) or write to us at 2116 South 17th Street, Mattoon, IL 61938. If you are a California resident and you wish to submit a verifiable consumer rights request under the CCPA, you can complete our online form at [www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request) or call our toll-free number at 1-833-679-0181.

OUR WEBSITE
-----------

**Last Updated: January 31, 2023**

Consolidated Communications (“we,” “us,” or “our”) operates the www.consolidated.com and certain affiliated websites, including our customer portal (collectively, the “Sites”). This Website Privacy Policy applies to the Sites as well as your use of our mobile applications.

This Website Privacy Policy describes the types of information that we may collect or you may provide to us when you register with, access or use the Sites and should be read in conjunction with our Website Terms of Use ([www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/website-terms-of-use](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/website-terms-of-use)). This Privacy Policy also describes our practices for collecting, using, disclosing, and maintaining such information.

This Website Privacy Policy does not alter the terms of any other agreement that you may have with us. Your use of the Sites constitutes your acceptance of this Website Privacy Policy. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR POLICIES AND PRACTICES, DO NOT ACCESS OR USE THE SITES. By accessing or using the Sites or any Consolidated Communication mobile application, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Website Privacy Policy.

1. ### Personal Information We Collect.
    
    “Personal information” is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person.

We may use links throughout the Sites to provide you with the opportunity to contact us via email to ask questions, request information and materials, or provide comments and suggestions (for example, if you visit [www.consolidated.com/contact-us](https://www.consolidated.com/contact-us) and complete our general online request form, we may receive your name or business name, address, email, account number, phone, and your message to us).  We may also collect information about you if you utilize our on-line chat function ([www.consolidated.com/chat](https://www.consolidated.com/chat)) in order to assist you with account related transactions, respond to your requests or authenticate your account information.

**Social Media.**When you interact with us through various social media, for example, by liking us on Facebook or following us on Twitter, we may collect aggregated or de-identified information about you. Unless you provide us with information in connection with a request for service or support, or you consent to provide us with information to participate in on-line promotional campaigns or similar offerings, we do not use social media platforms to collect personally identifiable information about you. However, please note that the information that you share with others from your social network may depend on your privacy settings. You should always review and adjust your privacy settings on social media platforms and third-party websites and services.

5. ### Information We Receive from Third Parties.
    
    We may receive information about you (including personal information) from third parties. For example, if you are on another website and you opt in to receive information from us, the third party website will forward to us your email address and other information about you so that we may contact you as requested. We may combine the information we receive from these third parties with information we collect through the Sites. In those cases, we will apply this Website Privacy Policy to any personal information received, unless we have disclosed otherwise.

7. ### Automatic Data Collection; Technologies Used to Automatically Collect Information.
    
    Whenever you visit or interact with the Sites, we, as well as our service providers, may use assorted technologies that automatically or passively collect information about how the Sites are accessed and used.  We refer to this information as “_traffic data_.” Traffic data is non-identifying and may include browser type, device type used to access the Sites (i.e., computer or mobile device), operating system, “click path” taken through the Sites, your use of features on the Sites, and persona or other usage information. This information helps us manage, improve and customize the Sites.

Technologies we use on the Sites to collect traffic data, directly or through our service providers, may include cookies (data files placed on your computer or other devices used to access the Sites), analytics software (e.g., Google Analytics) and pixel tags (transparent graphic images, sometimes called web beacons or tracking beacons, placed on a web page or in an email, which indicates that a page or email has been viewed).

10. ### How We Use Information We Collect.
    
    We collect and use your personal information for a variety of business purposes, including responding to your questions or requests, to provide the products and services that you request, to communicate with you, and to do all things necessary to administer the Sites, and manage, protect and improve them. We may also collect de-identified information about anonymous web visitors for the purposes of identifying potential interest in our commercial services. This information may include company name and the industry of the entity associated with traffic to our site. As we mentioned above, we also use the traffic data we collect to improve the Sites, to understand the effectiveness of marketing campaigns and to customize your experience.

12. ### Information We Share with Others.
    
    We may share your personal information and other information we collect with our affiliates or third party service providers that require access to your personal information for business purposes. We may also share de-identified information about anonymous web visitors with third parties for the purposes of retargeting visitors to our website with ads on other third-party sites. We may disclose personal information to service providers to protect the security and integrity of the Sites, to correct technical problems and malfunctions on the Sites, to technically process your information, to facilitate product and service support or to take precautions against liability. We also may provide your personal information to service providers who provide services on our behalf. If you request services via a mobile device, your request will be transmitted via your mobile carrier’s network and your carrier may have access to it. All above exclude text messaging originator opt-in data and consent; this information will not be shared with any third parties. Consult your carrier’s privacy policy for additional information.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in connection with a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of assets, reorganization or liquidation of our business. We reserve the right to disclose any personal information as needed if that information is requested by law enforcement agencies or if we are required to do so by law, treaty, regulation, subpoena, court order, or by a government entity. We also may disclose your personal information to third parties if we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to conduct investigations of possible breaches of law, to cooperate in any legal investigation, or to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating any agreement with us.

15. ### Do-Not-Track Requests; Third-Party Tracking.
    
    Unless your browser settings are configured to make your online activities and information about those activities (such as traffic data as described above) invisible to usage analytics tools, our Sites may track your usage through cookies. To opt out of being retargeted with Consolidated Communications ads on third-party sites due to your use of www.consolidated.com, click the “[Do Not Track](#donottrack)” button at the bottom of this page. Please note that this may not exclude you from online advertising by Consolidated Communications that is not related to your use of our Sites. Also, please be aware that we cannot control third-party tracking of your usage on our Sites and there may be some third-party tracking that occurs without our knowledge or consent.

17. ### Our Cookie Policy.

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text files stored on your computer or mobile device’s browser directory. Cookies are created when you use your browser to visit most websites, including our Sites and mobile applications. Cookies enable our Sites to remember your actions and preferences (such as login and customized display preferences), so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the Site.

**What types of data do our Sites collect through our use of cookies**?

Like many service providers, we use cookies and other technologies to collect and analyze information about you and your usage of our Sites. We also use cookies to evaluate, deliver and personalize our content and your web experience. Our Sites use first party cookies to track street address, city, state and ZIP code if a consumer enters it onto the Site, which allows the Site to be tailored to that user. We may also use IP addresses to capture de-identified users’ ZIP code for purposes of tailoring site content. With our multi-state market footprint, diverse service portfolios and different support organizations, this information allows us to provide an accurate online shopping experience and tailored access to regionalized customer support resources. Our Sites also use various cookies that keep track of whether a user has visited the Site before. This type of cookie is just a text file on the user’s computer that communicates with our Site. We do not collect any identifiable personal information through these cookies for marketing or non-essential purposes.

We also use a number of third-party cookies and pixel tracking codes to improve your browsing experience, to show you personalized content, provide targeted ads based on your location and content interests, and to analyze our website traffic. None of these technologies track or collect de-aggregated, identifiable personal information.

We also use email addresses collected from customers and prospects that have opted in to receive marketing emails from us for the purpose of serving Consolidated Communications ads through Gmail, Facebook, LinkedIn and/or other online advertising platforms.

Finally, when visitors enter personal or business information through an online form on our Sites or mobile applications, we use it to contact the user at their request and to properly identify the internal team/individual who should be assigned to contact that person (i.e., customer service vs. technical support, or call center vs direct sales and the appropriate direct sales representative assigned to a geographic territory). When business owners request information about business services or download white papers or similar premium content, we may pass that information through to a third-party marketing automation platform, which store that information on our behalf for our internal marketing purposes. By completing these website forms, the visitor is requesting contact and consenting to the sharing of this information for these purposes.

**How can I opt out of certain targeted on-line advertising or delete or refuse to accept cookies?**

You may opt out of being retargeted with Consolidated Communications ads on third-party websites by going to the bottom of this page and clicking on the “[Do Not Track](#donottrack)” button. Please note that this action may not exclude you from online advertising by Consolidated Communications that is not related to your use of our Sites.

In addition, most browsers allow you to delete or refuse to accept cookies. To learn how you may be able to reduce the number of cookies you receive from us, or delete cookies that have already been installed in your browser’s cookie folder, please refer to your browser’s help menu or other instructions related to your browser. If you do disable cookies, please be aware that some features and services on the Sites may not work as intended and you may not have access to all of the services and features we may offer.

29. ### Third-Party Links.
    
    The Sites may contain links to third-party websites that are not controlled by us. These links are made available to you as a convenience, and you agree to use these links at your own risk. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such third-party websites. This Website Privacy Policy only applies to information we collect from you while you are on the Sites. If you navigate to a third-party website from the Sites, we strongly encourage you to review and become familiar with that third-party website’s own privacy policy and statements. Use of third-party social networking websites, such as Twitter, Facebook and LinkedIn, are governed by the privacy policies and practices of those websites.

31. ### Children.
    
    The Sites are not intended for use by children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from such individuals. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of any such individual, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

33. ### Shine the Light.
    
    Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, California residents have the right to request from a business with whom the California resident has an established business relationship what types of personal information, if any, the business shares with third parties for direct marketing purposes by such third parties and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information in the immediately preceding calendar year.  Consolidated Communications does not share personal information of our California residents with third parties for purposes of direct marketing third party products or services.

35. ### Notice to Residents of Countries Outside the United States.
    
    We are headquartered in the United States and currently our services are only intended for individuals located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, be advised that any information you provide to us will be transferred to and stored in the United States and that, by submitting information to us, you explicitly authorize its transfer and storage within the United States. We will protect the privacy and security of personal information according to this Website Privacy Policy regardless of where it is processed or stored.

37. ### Changes to Privacy Policy.
    
    We reserve the right to change or replace this Website Privacy Policy at our sole discretion at any time and we encourage you to review this Website Privacy Policy periodically. If we make material changes to this Website Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Website Privacy Policy on this page. Any changes to the Website Privacy Policy will become effective upon posting of the revised policy. Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of changes constitutes your agreement to such changes.

39. ### Contact Us.

To contact us regarding this Website Privacy Policy, please call 1.844.YOUR.CCI (1.844.968.7224), submit an online request at [www.consolidated.com/contact-us](https://www.consolidated.com/contact-us) or write to us at 121 South 17th Street, Mattoon, IL 61938.  If you are a California resident and you wish to submit a verifiable consumer rights request under the CCPA, you can complete our online form at [www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request) or call our toll-free number at 1-833-679-0181. 

43. ### Do Not Track.

To opt out of being retargeted on third-party sites with Consolidated Communications ads as a result of your use of www.consolidated.com, please click "Do Not Track" button below. Please note that this action may not exclude you from online advertising by Consolidated Communications that is not related to your use of our Sites.

* * *

#### State Privacy Notices

**Notice to Maine Residents – Your Rights under Maine’s 2019 Internet Privacy Law**

If you are a Maine resident, you have certain rights, pursuant to the 2019 "Act to Protect the Privacy of Online Customer Information" (or the "Maine Privacy Act"). The Maine Privacy Act requires Internet service providers to take reasonable security measures to protect a customer's personal information and prohibits providers from using, disclosing, selling or permitting access to a customer's personal information unless the customer provides express, affirmative consent to do so, subject to certain limited exceptions. Further, a provider may not refuse service, charge a penalty or fail to provide a discount based on a customer's decision to provide or not provide such consent. For subscribers to our services, Consolidated Communications uses, discloses, sells and permits access to personal information only in accordance with the methods set forth in our Privacy Policy. Users of our Sites may opt out of certain targeted on-line advertising or delete or refuse to accept cookies as further described in our Website Privacy Policy.

**Notice to California Residents – Your CCPA Rights**

If you are a California resident, you have certain rights, pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act (or “CCPA”). These CCPA rights may only apply in certain circumstances and are subject to certain exemptions. Please see the table below for a summary of your rights. You can exercise these rights using the contact details below.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Right to Know** | As a California resident, you have the right to request that we disclose what personal information and sensitive personal information we collect, use, disclose, share and/or sell. |
| **Right to Request Deletion** | As a California resident, you have a right to request the deletion of your personal information and sensitive personal information collected or maintained by us. |
| **Right to Limit Use or Disclosure** | As a California resident, you have a right to limit the use and disclosure of your sensitive personal information if used for reasons other than those allowed by the CCPA (information necessary for providing, billing and collecting for your services).<br><br>All sensitive personal information that we collect or disclose is used for the reasons allowed by the CCPA. |
| **Right to Opt Out of Sale or Sharing** | As a California resident, you have a right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information.<br><br>We do not sell your personal information. The only personal information that is shared as defined in the CCPA, is information collected when you visit our websites or mobile applications such as your IP address and general geographical location. Our websites use first and third party cookies and pixel tracking codes. You may opt out of the use of these cookies and codes by clicking the “Do Not Track” button in the Do Not Track information under Our Website Section of our Privacy Policy. |
| **Right to Correct** | As a California resident, you have a right to request correction of inaccurate personal information maintained by us. |
| **Right to Non-Discrimination** | As a California resident, you have a right to non-discriminatory treatment and no retaliation by us for exercising any of your CCPA rights. |
| **Authorized Agent** | As a California resident, you can exercise your CCPA rights or you can designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. |
| **Contact Us for More Information** | If you have questions about Your CCPA Rights, please contact us by phone at 1-888-890-6767 or write to us at 2116 South 17th Street, Mattoon, IL 61938. If you or your authorized agent would like to submit a consumer rights request under the CCPA, you can do so by clicking on the following link: [www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request). |

### Notice at Collection

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of personal information** | **Sources of personal information** | **Business or commercial purpose for which information was collected and length of time retained** | **Categories of third parties with whom the business sells or shares personal information as defined in the CCPA** |
| Identifiers: name, date of birth, telephone number, mailing address, service address, email address, internet protocol address, unique number assigned to identify the device used to access our websites, account number | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business, including maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, billing for service and collecting payments, verifying customer information, providing advertising or marketing services, utilizing analytic services or providing similar services on behalf of the business or service provider; detecting security incidents, protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and prosecuting those responsible for that activity; undertaking activities to verify, upgrade, enhance or maintain the quality of our products or services.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Information in Customer Records related to services provided and used | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business or service provider, including maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, processing or fulfilling orders and transactions, verifying customer information, processing payments, providing financing, providing advertising or marketing services, utilizing analytic services, or providing similar services on behalf of the business or service provider; responding, on a priority basis, to outages or trouble tickets for certain customers that provide us with; detecting security incidents, protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and prosecuting those responsible for that activity; undertaking activities to verify, upgrade, enhance or maintain the quality of our products or services.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Information on your use of our communications services including Internet or other electronic network activity: IP addresses assigned, protocol and destination addresses, website addresses received, bandwidth used, telephone calls made and received | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business or service provider, including maintaining or servicing accounts, billing, providing customer service, processing or fulfilling orders and transactions, providing advertising or marketing services, utilizing analytic services, or providing similar services on behalf of the business or service provider; responding, on a priority basis, to outages or trouble tickets for certain customers that provide us with; detecting security incidents, protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and prosecuting those responsible for that activity; undertaking activities to verify, upgrade, enhance or maintain the quality of our products or services interaction; undertaking internal research for technological development and demonstration.<br><br>Retained: Information like dynamic IP addresses assigned and internet usage is maintained for approximately 45 to 120 days. The retention of information as to non-toll calls made varies from approximately 0 to 90 days. Information about toll calls and static IP addresses assigned is maintained for at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Internet or other electronic network activity regarding your interaction with our Sites or advertisements ( IP address, general geographical location) | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business, including providing analytic services; auditing related to a current interaction with the consumer and concurrent transactions, and auditing compliance with this specification and other standards; detecting security incidents, protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and prosecuting those responsible for that activity; short-term, transient use, although no personal information is disclosed to third parties and is not used to build a profile about a consumer or otherwise alter an individual consumer’s experience outside the current interaction; undertaking internal research for technological development and demonstration.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | Information is shared with/disclosed to third party traffic data analytic provider e.g. Google Analytics |
| Commercial information (products or services purchased, obtained or considered, other purchase or consuming histories or tendencies) | Directly from you; via our service providers | Auditing related to a current interaction with the consumer and concurrent transactions; performing services on behalf of the business including processing or fulfilling orders and transactions, verifying customer information and processing payments; undertaking activities to verify, upgrade, enhance or maintain the quality of our products or services.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Audio, electronic, visual, thermal or olfactory data | Directly from you; via our service providers | Voicemail recordings utilized to verify and archive account holder service requests involving matters such as billing and troubleshooting.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Geolocation information (Based on service location) | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business, including tax and regulatory billing compliance; verifying the market location of customers in order to provision and offer services.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Characteristics of protected classifications under California or federal law (sex/gender, age (over 40): age, disability) | Directly from you; via our service providers | Voluntarily provided. Used in performing services on behalf of the business such as responding, on a priority basis, to outages or trouble tickets or prevention of service disconnections or in providing accessibility accommodations.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of sensitive personal information collected** | **Sources of personal information** | **Business or commercial purpose for which it was collected and length of time retained** | **Categories of third parties with whom the business shares personal information** |
| Identifier: Social Security number, Driver’s license, State ID, Password | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business, including maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, billing for service and collecting payments, verifying customer information, detecting security incidents, protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and prosecuting those responsible for that activity.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |
| Limited Medical Information | Directly from you; via our service providers | Voluntarily provided limited medical information for the purpose of prioritizing outage responses and prevention of service suspensions. | N/a |
| Financial Payment Information Service Account Login Credentials | Directly from you; via our service providers | Performing services on behalf of the business or service provider, including maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, processing or fulfilling orders and transactions, verifying customer information, processing payments, providing financing, detecting security incidents, protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and prosecuting those responsible for that activity.<br><br>Retained: For at least four years after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations.<br><br>Financial payment source information is not retained. | N/a |
| Contents of your email and telephone calls while using our services | Directly from you; via our service providers | Email and voice mail content is retained while customer has our company services and until customer deletes messages or discontinues service and then they are deleted.<br><br>Retained: For 90 days after you discontinue services based on applicable laws and regulations. | N/a |

While we do disclose personal information with service providers for the business purpose of performing services specified in our written contracts, we do not sell or share any personal information to or with third parties for their own business or commercial purposes and have not done so during the last 12 months. We do not sell or share personal information of minors under 16 years of age and we do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 18.

To submit a verifiable consumer rights request under the CCPA, you or your authorized agent can do so by using either of the following designated request methods: call our toll-free number at 1-888-890-6767 or complete our online form at [www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-rights-request). We may ask for certain information about you to verify that the request is being made in accordance with applicable law.

If you would like to print a copy of this Privacy Policy, please select the “Print” button in your web browser.

Terms, conditions, charges and restrictions apply. Speed and uninterrupted service not guaranteed.  
Not all services available in all areas. Services and pricing subject to change.

© 2024 Consolidated Communications

[Privacy Policy](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-policy), [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/do-not-sell-my-personal-information), [Notice at Collection](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies/privacy-policy#notice), [Broadband Consumer Labels](https://www.consolidated.com/broadband-labels) and other [Terms & Policies](https://www.consolidated.com/support/terms-policies). [Notice at Collection](https://www.consolidated.com/careers/notice-at-collection)

×
